Guide to the Time Inc. Time-Life News Service Records 1935-1987 MS 3009-RG 14
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Staff Files, 1936-1987; 46.8 Linear feet in 49 record cartons
  - Subseries IV.B. Ex-Staff Files, 1943-1987; 16.55 Linear feet in 18 record cartons
    - Wheeler, Keith, 1953-1961 (Offsite-box 3236, Folder 15)
    - White, Arthur, 1979-1986 (Offsite-box 3236, Folder 16-17)
    - White, Arthur [RESTRICTED], 1966-1986 (Offsite-box R54)
    - White, William, 1944-1955 (Offsite-box 3236, Folder 18-19)
    - Whitmore, James, 1950-1965 (Offsite-box 3236, Folder 20-23)
    - Whitney, Thomas, 1949-1953 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 1)
    - Whitney, Leslie [RESTRICTED], 1983-1984 (Offsite-box R54)
    - Wierzynski, Greg, 1969-1986 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 2-3)
    - Wierzynski, Greg [RESTRICTED], 1969-1987 (Offsite-box R54)
    - Wilcox, Richard, 1944 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 4)
    - Williams, Cynthia [RESTRICTED], 1975-1981 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Wittaya, Prasong, 1953-1954 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 5)
    - Wolf, Diether [RESTRICTED], 1969-1985 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Wood, David, 1972-1980 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 6-7)
    - Wood, David [RESTRICTED], 1972-1980 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Wurmstedt, Robert, 1977-1986 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 8-11)
    - Wurmstedt, Robert [RESTRICTED], 19877-1986 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Yang, John [RESTRICTED], 1981-1986 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Young, Connie Louise [RESTRICTED], 1969 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Zacks, Richard, 1981-1983 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 12)
    - Zacks, Richard [RESTRICTED], 1983 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Zeitlin, David, 1961 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 13)
    - Zich, Arthur M. Jr., 1964-1969 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 14)
    - Ziegler, Onetta [RESTRICTED], 1973-1985 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Zinder, Harry, 1944-1947 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 15-16)
  - Subseries IV.C. Stringer Files, 1949-1987; 3.65 Linear feet in 5 record cartons
    The Stringer Files cover the period of 1949 to 1987 and contain a mix of biographical and personnel files for Time-Life News Service staff, correspondents, and bureau chiefs designated as stringers by the Time Inc. Archives at the time they received the records. Included in this subseries are stringer expense reports, cash advance forms, check requisition forms, intern project application forms, expense reports, receipts, invoices, press kits, writing samples, biographical data forms, photographs, negatives, lists of stringers, payment schedules, lists of bureau assignments, list of telex rental fees, dispatches, resumes, foreign travel worksheets, job applications, bureau finance reports, visa forms, and correspondence. The correspondence included in this series discusses advances, budgets, bookkeeping issues, payments, contact information, financial plans, salaries, intern selection, travel, health, bureau updates, telex charges, treatment of stringers, resignation, staffing changes, assignments, expenses, vacation, transfers, travel schedules, press accreditation, meetings, and retirements.
    - Stringers: General, 1961-1962, 1970-1985 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 17-19)
    - Stringers: General [RESTRICTED], 1978-1982 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Stringers: Data, 1961-1963, 1969-1971 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 20)
    - Stringers: Data [RESTRICTED], 1969 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Abisheganaden, Felix, 1959 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 21)
    - An, Pham Xuan, 1971-1984 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 22)
    - Anderson, Jon, 1984-1986 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 23-24)
    - Anderson, Jon [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Annan, Ruth, 1974 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 25)
    - Bass, Isabel, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3237, Folder 26)
    - Bentley, Logan, 1962-1963 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 1)
    - Blewett, Jennis, 1977-1979 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 2)
    - Bonde, Arne, 1964-1966, 1977 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 3)
    - Bonnay, Charles, 1961-1962 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 4)
    - Boulay, Pierre, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 5)
    - Brake, Brian, 1960-1964 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 6)
    - Brew, Douglas, 1978, 1984, undated (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 7)
    - Brew, Douglas [RESTRICTED], 1979-1983 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Briggs, Olin, 1977 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 8)
    - Buckman, John, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 9)
    - Buderi, Bob, 1981-1987 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 10-11)
    - Buderi, Bob [RESTRICTED], 1985-1986 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Burgess, John, 1979-1981 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 12)
    - C: Miscellaneous, 1969-1972 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 13)
    - Cameron, Denis: Injury, 1974 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 14)
    - Cameron, Denis: Inquiry [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Campus Stringers, 1966-1970 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 15)
    - Carter, Tom, 1962-1963 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 16)
    - Carter, Tom [RESTRICTED], 1962 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Casey, Marty [RESTRICTED], 1983-1985 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Cauley, Leslie, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 17)
    - Chang, Lawrence, 1967-1971 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 18)
    - Challard, Jean-Pierre, 1975 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 19)
    - Chelminski, Rudy, 1977 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 20)
    - Cornell, John, 1977 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 21)
    - Danforth, Ken, 1972-1978 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 22)
    - De La Cal, Martha, 1976-1977, 1983 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 23)
    - Devereux, Ed, 1969 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 24)
    - Dinges, John, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 25)
    - Dohrn, Klaus, 1963-1970 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 26)
    - Du Bois, Larry, 1970 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 27)
    - Endt, Friso, 1963-1973 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 28)
    - England, Ken, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 29)
    - Englund, Steve, 1976 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 30)
    - Erlick, June, 1981-1986 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 31)
    - Fares, Louis, 1976-1980 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 32)
    - Finnegan, Phil, 1983-1985 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 33)
    - Finnegan, Phil [RESTRICTED], 1984-1985 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Fitchett, Joe, 1973 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 34)
    - Freeman, Clive, 1970 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 35)
    - Galling, Walter, 1977-1986 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 36)
    - Galling, Walter [RESTRICTED], 1978-1985 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Glass, Charles, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 37)
    - Graham, Loral, 1974 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 38)
    - Gross, Neil, 1983-1987 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 39)
    - Gross, Neil [RESTRICTED], 1983-1986 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Grundy, Trevor, 1978-1980 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 40)
    - Gunson, Phil, 1984 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 41)
    - Hanson, Chris, 1978 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 42)
    - Hardin, Blanche, 1969-1972 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 43)
    - Hawley, Elizabeth, 1960-1967 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 44)
    - Hawley, Elizabeth [RESTRICTED], 1967 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Hazelton, 1979 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 45)
    - Honegger, Pierre, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 46)
    - Honey, Martha, 1983-1984 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 47)
    - Honey, Martha [RESTRICTED], 1983-1984 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Hoover, Eleanor, 19870-1971 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 48)
    - Iseman, Peter, 1970 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 49)
    - Johnson, Mary, 1952-1954, 1964-1966 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 50)
    - Johnson, Tom, 1977-1985 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 51-52)
    - Johnson, Tom [RESTRICTED], 1985 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Jones, Christopher, 1980-1982 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 53)
    - Jones, Christopher [RESTRICTED], 1981 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Jurado, Jorge, 1952-1969, 1976 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 54)
    - Jurado, Jorge [RESTRICTED], 1970 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Kepp, Micahel, 1986 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 55)
    - Keyworth, Lance, 1951, 1958-1969, 1976 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 56)
    - Khliff, Edmond, 1981 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 57)
    - Kramer, Jack, 1976 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 58)
    - Lawton, David, 1971-1978 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 59)
    - Lawton, David [RESTRICTED], 1973 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Lee, Young, 1965-1980 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 60)
    - Lee, Young [RESTRICTED], 1969, 1970 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Lindley, Nona, 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 61)
    - Loayza, Tomas, 1949-1967, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3238, Folder 62)
    - Loughran, Tim, 1982 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 1)
    - Malik, Ghulam, 1980 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 2)
    - Mallin, Jay, 1957-1970, 1976-1983 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 3)
    - Martin, Carolyn, 1983 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 4)
    - McCabe, Robert K., 1961-1970 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 5)
    - Meister, Knud, 1950-1970 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 6)
    - Meister, Knud [RESTRICTED], 1959 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Meyer, Leszek, 1967 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 7)
    - Minetree, Harry, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 8)
    - Modiano, Mario, 1965-1974 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 9)
    - Mohs, Mayo [RESTRICTED], 1966-1967 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Montenegro, Walter, 1953, 1964-1966 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 10)
    - Morris, Fred, 1972-1974 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 11)
    - Nanji, Ghulam, 1963-1969, 1975 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 12)
    - Oatway, Ronald, 1958-1965, 1971 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 13)
    - Oulahan, Richard, 1945, 1959-1961, 1971 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 14)
    - Paterson, Adolphus, 1960-1979, 1985 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 15-16)
    - Persaud, Paul, 1962-1963 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 17)
    - Planet, Mario, 1950-1968, 1974-1980 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 18-20)
    - Planet, Mario [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Quinn, Jon, 1984 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 21)
    - R: Miscellaneous, 1961-1971 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 22)
    - Raein, Pariz, 1963-1985 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 23-24)
    - Raein, Parviz [RESTRICTED], 1970-1985 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Raphael, Alison, 1977-1980 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 25)
    - Raphael, Alison [RESTRICTED], 1980 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Reuter, Henry, 1959-1965 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 26)
    - Riddle, John, 1976-1982 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 27-28)
    - Ring, Wilson, 1985-1986 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 29)
    - Robb, Patricia, 1982-1985 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 30)
    - Robins, Eric, 1969-1979 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 31)
    - Robins, Eric [RESTRICTED], 1964, 1979 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Rosenberg, Robert, 1981-1982 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 32)
    - Ruangdej, Surin, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 33)
    - Ruandej, Surin [RESTRICTED], undated (Offsite-box R55)
    - Santos, Guillermo, 1958-1972 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 34)
    - Saporiti, Piero, 1967-1971 (Offsite-box 3239, Folder 35)
    - Saporiti, Piero [RESTRICTED], 1967-1971 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Shamberg, Michael, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 1)
    - Shapiro, Donald, 1970 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 2)
    - Shaw, John, 1976-1980 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 3)
    - Shay, Reg, 1969, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 4)
    - Shay, Reg [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Singh, Amaranth, 1983 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 5)
    - Singh, Amarnath [RESTRICTED], 1983 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Smiley, Xan, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 6)
    - Smiley, Xan [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Sonzski, William [RESTRICTED], 1986 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Spelman, Franz, 1958-1970 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 7)
    - Spelman, Franz [RESTRICTED], 1959 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Spencer, Terence, 1955-1964 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 8)
    - Spencer, Terence [RESTRICTED], 1961 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Stephen, Ignatius, 1962 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 9)
    - Stevens, Ed, 1971 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 10)
    - Stichova, Eva, 1979-1984 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 11)
    - Stocken, Terence, 1949, 1957-1966, 1976 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 12)
    - T: Miscellaneous, 1959-1962 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 13)
    - Thomas, Jergen, 1977 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 14)
    - Vandelinde, Wibo, 1978-1982 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 15)
    - W: Miscellaneous, 1954-1958, 1966 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 16)
    - W: Miscellaneous [RESTRICTED], 1971 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Wagdi, Mahamed, 1955-1977 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 17)
    - Wagdi, Mahamed: Case, 1975 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 18)
    - Wagdi, Mohamed [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Weinraub, Judy [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Offsite-box R55)
    - Weinstein, Allen, 1977 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 19)
    - Wright, John, 1986 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 20)
- Series V. Dispatches and Article Research Files, 1969-1979; 1.75 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
  Benjamin Cate is first listed in the departments heads list in 1966 as a bureau chief of the Houston office. In 1970, Cate was transferred overseas and placed in charge of the Bonn office. By 1972, he had been transferred back to the main offices in New York where he worked as a deputy chief of correspondents through 1974. By 1978, Cate had left his position as deputy chief and became chief of the Chicago bureau of the Time-Life News Service. He remained in this position until 1981 when he became the chief of the Beverly Hills bureau. In 1985, he was no longer listed as a bureau chief in the departments lists and was instead listed as a senior correspondent. After this point, Cate no longer appears in department heads lists.
  The Dispatch and Article Research Files cover the period 1969 through 1979 and contain two sets of materials. While the majority of dispatches were transferred and filed with the editorial reference files when the Time Research Center was created, these were materials were missed and found loose with unrelated corporate editorial files. While these materials may have been found with unrelated materials, they were originally produced and collected by the news service and will be stored with their materials. Additional dispatches can be found throughout the Time-Life News Service records.
  The first set of materials appears to have been mainly collected by Time-Life News service staff memember Benjamin Cate regarding the Chappaquiddick incident involving Ted Kennedy. While the materials were mainly collected by Cate, there are also materials from after he left the news service. It is unclear who collected the materials after Cate since they were found with the Laurence Barrett files but appear to be unrelated to those materials. The Chappaquiddick materials include dispatches, lists of contacts, clippings, car manuals, investigation notes, investigation policies, court hearing and testimony documents, biographical data sheets, lists of assignments, telephone call logs, car accident forms, rental care agreements and correspondence.
  The second set of materials are dispatches with details about Howard Hughes, Jackie Kennedy, Scientology, and United Presidents as well as their wives and cabinent members.
  - Chappaquiddick: Arena, Jim: Interview, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 21)
  - Chappaquiddick: Articles and Clippings, 1974-1979 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 22-24)
  - Chappaquiddick: Assignments, 1974 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 25)
  - Chappaquiddick: Car Accident Report, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 26)
  - Chappaquiddick: Character Witnesses, 1969 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 27)
  - Chappaquiddick: Clippings, 1974 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 28)
  - Chappaquiddick: Dinis, Edmund, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 29)
  - Chappaquiddick: Dispatches, 1979 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 30)
  - Chappaquiddick: Dispatches: Extras, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 31)
  - Chappaquiddick: Dispatches and Notes, 1969-1974, undated (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 32-33)
  - Chappaquiddick: Grand Jury and Names, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 34)
  - Chappaquiddick: Inquest Documents: Vol. II - V, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3240, Folder 35-40)
  - Chappaquiddick: Kennedy, Ted: Fact Sheets, 1974 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 1)
  - Chappaquiddick: Letters, 1974 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 2)
  - Chappaquiddick: Look, Christopher Jr., 1974 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 3)
  - Chappaquiddick: Miscellaneous, 1969-1979 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 4-5)
  - Chappaquiddick: Newberg, Esther, 1969 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 6)
  - Chappaquiddick: On the Island, 1974 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 7)
  - Chappaquiddick: Peachy, Russell E., 1974 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 8)
  - Chappaquiddick: People to See, 1969 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 9)
  - Chappaquiddick: Plymouth Valiant, 1968-1974 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 10)
  - Chappaquiddick: Telephone Numbers, Calls, and Notes, 1969 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 11)
  - Chappaquiddick: Three Men in a Boat, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 12)
  - Chappaquiddick: Updates: Takes I-VIII, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 13-14)
  - Chappaquiddick: Updates: Take V and Overview, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 15)
  - Chappaquiddick: Weather, undated (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 16)
  - Hughes, Howard and Clifford Irving, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 17-20)
  - Kennedy, Jackie, 1960-1961 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 21-27)
  - Miscellaneous: Chappaquiddick, Inquest Exhibits, Charts, and etc., 1969-1979 (Offsite-box 3241, Folder 28-29)
  - Scientology, 1983 (Offsite-box 3242, Folder 1)
  - Scientology: Folo: Time/Religion, 1983 (Offsite-box 3242, Folder 2-3)
  - Scientology: Time/Religion, 1972, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 3242, Folder 4-5)
  - Third Person Theory: Checklist, undated (Offsite-box 3242, Folder 6)
  - United States Presidents, Cabinet Members and their Wives, 1959-1961 (Offsite-box 3242, Folder 7-12)
- Series VI. Masthead Files, 1941-1947, 1969-1981; .5 Linear feet in 1 record carton
  The Masthead Files contain materials from 1941 to 1947 and 1969 to 1981. Included in this series are Time mastheads and correspondence discussing masthead changes concerning Time-Life News Service staff. While the names of Time-Life News Service staff are featured on the correspondence, it is unclear who collected these materials due to the inclusion of Time editorial staff names. Time editorial staff were sometimes the senders or recipients of these pieces of correspondence. The main names featured on these documents are Libby Waite, Emily Friedrich, Betty Valentine, Katherine McNevin, Ken Shaw, Edward Jamieson, Lou Glessman, Murray Gart, Jim Ostur, Richard Seamon, Pat Newman, Dorothy O'Keefe, Pat Lambert, Susan Hake, and Linda Vartoogian.
  - Changes, 1969-1981 (Offsite-box 3242, Folder 13-19)
  - News Service Alumni Study, 1941-1947 (Offsite-box 3242, Folder 20)